# Hyeonmin Lee

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

EMAIL: hmlee@mmlab.snu.ac.kr

ADDRESS: Network Convergence and Security Lab., 5F, Building 301, 1,

Gwankak-ro, Gwanak-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

HOMEPAGE: https://hyeonmin-lee.github.io///

I'm a Ph.D. candidate in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at Seoul National University, advised by Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon.

My research interests focus on network security and (network) security measurement: Are we using the network correctly and safely (especially, about security protocols)? How can we make the network (more) safely?

• RESEARCH INTERESTS: Network Security and its Measurement

# **EDUCATION**

MAR 2016 - FEB 2022 **Ph.D. Candidate**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

- Dissertation: "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- Advisor: Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon

MAR 2011 - FEB 2016 **B.S.**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

FALL 2014

**Visiting Student**, Information Technology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

## **PUBLICATION**

#### Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP (to appear)

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2022

#### A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2020

# Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Song

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information (JCCI), Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

# TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things

Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon Elsevier Computer Networks (SCI-E)

# PROJECT EXPERIENCES

Apr 2020 - Present	Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle  • Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)  • Role: Researcher / Programmer
Mar 2021 - Nov 2021	Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis
	<ul> <li>Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security &amp; Cryptology (KIISC)</li> <li>Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / Researcher / Programmer</li> </ul>
Apr 2016 - Dec 2020	<ul> <li>Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity</li> <li>Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)</li> <li>Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer</li> </ul>
FEB 2020 - Nov 2020	Research on GPU Acceleration for Fully Homomorphic Encryption  • Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC)  • Role: Programmer
SEP 2019	Developing High-performance Programming Environments and Computing
- APR 2020	<ul><li>Systems</li><li>Supported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)</li><li>Role: Programmer</li></ul>
Aug 2019 - Nov 2019	Research on Distributed Web Structure and Counterplan  • Supported by Korea Internet and Security Agency (KISA)  • Role: Researcher
SEP 2018	Research on Trust and Security Scheme for Interconnection of Heteroge-
- Nov 2018	<ul><li>neous Networks</li><li>Supported by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)</li><li>Role: Researcher</li></ul>
AUG 2016 - Feb 2019	Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model  • Supported by Giga KOREA Foundation  • Role: System Designer / Programmer
MAR 2016 - MAY 2016	Content Delivery Framework Using Spatial and Temporal Dynamics in Mobile Networks  • Supported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)  • Role: Programmer
JUL 2015 - DEC 2015	Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Low-power SoC  • Supported by Samsung Electronics  • Role: Programmer

### **PATENTS**

# Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof

- Registration No. 1022656110000
- Republic of Korea, Jun. 10, 2021

# Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System

- Registration No. 1020231150000
- Republic of Korea, Sep. 11, 2019

### EXPERIENCES

## MAY 2019

# Visiting Researcher

- AUG 2019

The Center for Cybersecurity, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, USA

• Topic: Measuring and analyzing the ecosystem of DANE protocol in Email

#### **SPRING 2016**

### **Teaching Assistant**

Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

• Class: Engineering Frontiers and Leadership 2

### **MISCELLANEOUS**

# Mar 2019

# **Expert Research Personnel** (military service)

- FEB 2022 S

Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

The expert research personnel system is a form of alternative military service in Republic of Korea, where the military service is fulfilled by conducting research at a domestic university or company for three years. I had not been involved in any military research project throughout the service.